Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/gabriel-guerrero-3245295 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Google Web Toolkit (GWT) Lucene PostgreSQL

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Gabriel Guerrero

Full Stack Developer

Greater Guildford Area, United Kingdom

Summary

Full Stack Engineer, more than 20 years of experience, expertise in Angular and Typescript for the front end and Java for the backend, but also can work in React, Node, Nest, Kotlin. Looking for contracts around the London area or close to Woking or remote.

Experience

EDF Trading Software Engineer August 2024 - Present (11 months) London Area, United Kingdom

Working as full stack engineer using angular and c#

Turner & Townsend Software Developer June 2023 - February 2024 (9 months) Greater London, England, United Kingdom

I contributed to the Hive Portal by developing a new Project Management section to manage projects and

generate reports for the company's client portal mobile app. Additionally, I collaborated with the

Benchmarking Team to refactor the Benchmarking app, which is used to compare building project costs. These enhancements enabled new capabilities for the app's charts and reports.

The development was carried out using Angular, Angular Material, NgRx, Highcharts, NGINX, Docker, and a Python backend deployed on Google Cloud. I also improved the security of the Hive Portal by setting up the Content Security Policy (CSP) for their applications. Furthermore, I resolved several issues in their build

pipeline, which utilizes GitHub Actions, Nx, and Docker.

Turner & Townsend Software Developer September 2022 - April 2023 (8 months)

London

I worked with the Hive Portal team to develop several new sections. I created a curriculum generator that uses an individual's projects to generate curriculums. Additionally, I helped implement a Programme section, which groups multiple projects, allowing users to see the relationships between various projects, subprojects, organizations, and individuals involved.

These sections were developed using Angular, Angular Material, NgRx, Highcharts, and Docker, with a Python backend deployed on Google Cloud.

Medivet

Frontend Developer

March 2020 - August 2022 (2 years 6 months)

Watford, England, United Kingdom

At Medivet, I was involved in the development of three applications. For the Freedom Clinic App, I remade the clinic's app, Freedom, as a monorepo to allow different teams to develop various sections independently. The technologies used included Angular, Angular Material, WebSockets with SignalR, RxJS, NgRx, NgRx-Traits, Jest, Cypress, Angular CLI, and NX Console. The app was built as an NGINX Docker image using Azure Pipelines and deployed on Kubernetes hosted in Azure AKS, with the backend developed using .NET Core, SignalR microservices, and EF Microsoft SQL. For the New Client Portal, I developed a new client portal where users can register and book appointments. The portal was created using React, React-Query, Formik, Next.js, Auth0, GRPC, and App Insights. It was deployed to Azure AKS as a Node.js and Express Docker image, with the backend created using .NET Core Web API, GRPC, EF, and Microsoft SQL.

For the Old Purchase Order App, I upgraded the app from Java 8, Spring Boot 1.5, and Angular 5 to Java 17, Spring Boot 2.6, JPA, PostgreSQL, and Angular 14. I implemented new features, added Azure App Insights, and changed the setup to be deployed with an NGINX Docker image for the frontend and a Java Docker image for the backend in Azure AKS, using pipelines in DevOps.

Legal and General Full Stack Developer August 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 8 months) London, United Kingdom

At Legal and General, I contributed to the development of two web app projects, both now in production. The first project is an application for the public to register for an investment pension with Legal and General. This project utilized Angular 7, RxJS, NgRx, Angular Animations, Angular CLI,

Protractor for end-to-end testing. The application is deployed in an AWS S3 bucket, with Jenkins used for building using Git Flow. I also assisted with the backend, which employed microservices made with Java and Kotlin, GraphQL, Spring Boot, and PostgreSQL, all deployed to OpenShift Kubernetes. The second project is part of a larger initiative called "Manage Your Account." For this, we built a series of lazy-loaded wizards that allow retirees to collect money from their L&G pensions in various ways. Additionally, I created a library of UI components that are used across multiple projects. This project utilized Angular 8, RxJS, NgRx, and GraphQL with Apollo. For testing, we used Karma for unit testing and Protractor with Cucumber for end-to-end testing. The application is packaged in Docker with NGINX, uploaded to AWS ECR, and deployed to AWS Kubernetes EKS. Continuous integration was managed with Jenkins using GitHub Flow, with PRs merged only after passing unit and BDD tests. Both projects passed rigorous accessibility tests. On the backend, I worked with microservices built with Java and Kotlin, GraphQL, Spring Boot, and PostgreSQL, deployed to OpenShift Kubernetes.

and GraphQL with Apollo. For testing, we used Karma for unit testing and

Mimecast Senior Arquitect August 2007 - July 2018 (11 years) London, United Kingdom

TLDR: During my 11 years in mimecast I been involved in almost all of the multiple web apps the company offers, from their design to their architecture and implementation using initially GWT then angular js and then Angular with RXJS, NGRX and Typescript, with a Java backend using JAX-RS and Tomcat

(later Jetty), other technologies git, webpack, gulp, rpm , puppet , Docker, using Agile methodologies.

- Architect, design and implement Mimecast Personal Portal, a mail and calendar web client. Initially we created a framework called Sprinta made in GWT, Guice, Jackson and JBoss, with support of databiding, i18n, templating, lazy loading, later JBoss will be replace by Tomcat, this version will be use for around 5 years.
- At around 5 years I was the Lead Developer and Architect of a group 4 to
 6 devs which remade Mimecast Personal Portal using angularjs for the client
 and java jersey jetty for the backend and maven and grunt to build it.
- After that I started working as Architect and developer with a team of around
 13 devs to the remake of the Mimecast Admin Console, this presented several
 challenges because the admin console was made in a very old technology

and it had to be remade incrementally the new sections used angularjs and some special components were made so the old sections not yet remade were rendered in an iframe inside a tabbed component making them look like they were one app and allowing us to remake it sllowy.

• About around 1 year of using angularjs, Angular 2 was released and it was decided to migrate to Typescript and Angular 2, with RXJS and NGRX this was also challenging because it was also required to be migrated in chunks, we used ng upgrade to do a logic that allows us to run angulajs in some sections and Angular 2 in the new ones.

Avviato Inc Project Team Leader 2004 - February 2007 (3 years) Venezuela

Architect of the main project of the company the www.1800-Volunteer.com site for Points Of Light foundation in the US, design and lead the development of all the main functionalities of the site, the main technologies used by the site are Struts, Tiles, Hibernate over a OC4J server and a Oracle DB, to name a few of the functionalities designed and developed by me, a Google style search engine for the opportunities posted in the site, implemented using Apache Lucene, Java Concurrent API and Hibernate; the logic that manages all the I18N content of the site; a Email API that works with I18N and templates that can be edited by the user and add dynamic variables to the templates, a Volunteer Matching Engine used by the Volunteer Centers to search for volunteers registered in the site that have a set of necessary skills that are needed work in emergency opportunities.

As Project team lead, managed a group of 5 to 6 developers for the
development of the 1800 volunteer project during almost 3 years, used
Extreme Programming methodology, JIRA, Microsoft Project, Maven, and
CVS. Used to manage the development of the web site, increase the quality
of the project, the development speed of the team, the training time for new
developers, and improve the precision of the scoping and planning for new
functionality.

Education

Universidad Metropolitana (VE) (1997 - 2003)